STEPHEN GARRETT DEWYER

software developer | user experience designer

www.stephendewyerwebwork.com

Tucson, Arizona stephen.dewyer@stephengdewyer.info 248-766-8556

software development and **UX** design skills

- · Programming languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, C++, Python, PHP
- JavaScript compilers, frameworks and libraries: SvelteKit, Svelte, Next.js, React, Vue.js, Express, Handlebars
- DevOps: Agile
- Artificial intelligence
- Stylesheet languages: CSS 3
- Markup languages: HTML 5
- Server environments: Node
- **Development environments:** Visual Studio
- Database management systems: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Application programming interfaces: Representational state transfer (REST), GraphQL
- **UX design:** wire framing, prototyping, user research, user testing, information architecture, user flows, user interviews
- Digital media: Adobe Creative Cloud, photography, videography, graphic design, brand identity design, animation
- Prototyping: Figma
- eCommerce: Stripe
- Web accessibility standards: WCAG
- Version control systems: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket

awards and grants

Knight Arts Challenge Detroit matching \$20,000 grant for ∞ mile

John S. and James L. Knight Foundation 2014 - 2016

Detroit Chapter June 2014 \$1,000 grant for ∞ mile Awesome Foundation

2014

career objective

An award-winning software developer and UX designer with over ten years of experience creating groundbreaking web programs for organizations. Experienced in working with stakeholders to produce critically-acclaimed projects. Effective at developing creative software solutions to challenging problems that help empower businesses and communities.

professional experience

Founding Director, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer Art in Tech Services Inc.

April 2021 – present, Tucson, Arizona (relocated from Minneapolis, MN)

- Worked with clients to plan and achieve client goals, meeting or exceeding client expectations and accomplishing a 100% client satisfaction rate
- Designed, developed, deployed and maintained the company's website including a client portal that streamlined client collaboration
- Developed innovative software using art expertise and state-of-the-art digital technologies like SvelteKit and Next.js
- Directed the company to provide state-of-the-art digital services to create groundbreaking digital products using advancements in art and digital technology

Founder, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer **Public Arts Commission**

April 2017 – present, Tucson, Arizona (relocated from Minneapolis, MN)

- Designed, developed and deployed software programs including a campaign application management system, an endorsement management system and a publicly searchable database of all the organization's endorsements
- Developing a voter networking and organizing portal
- Conducted user tests for web prototypes with Board of Directors and art
- Grew Board of Directors by 233% to include leading voices in the art community by delivering strong leadership
- Responsible for overall direction of the non-profit, 501(c)(4) organization

UX Design Consultant (contract)

Turnberry Solutions

February - May 2022, Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Created high-fidelity prototypes to personalize dental insurance plan shopping in the Federal Employees Dental and Vision Insurance Program (FEDVIP)
- Helped empower teams to produce great UX design for enterprise web products
- Client: FedPoint

Web Developer and UX Designer / Co-Founding Editor ∞ mile (Infinite Mile LLC)

education

Master of Fine Arts (MFA) in Sculpture

Yale University School of Art 2009 – 2011, New Haven, Connecticut

Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA) *cum laude* in Art History, Theory & Criticism

Maryland Institute College of Art 2005 – 2008, Baltimore, Maryland

teaching experience

Lecturer

University of Detroit Mercy School of Architecture Digital Media Department

2015 – 2017, Detroit, Michigan

Special Lecturer

2015 – 2016, Rochester, Michigan

Lecturer

2014 – 2015, Rochester, Michigan Oakland University Department of Art & Art History

websites created

• 2021 – present

Art in Tech Services Inc www.artintechservices.com

• 2017 – present

Public Arts Commission

www.publicartscommission.org

• 2023

Suzanne Conti Quilts

https://suzannecontiquilts.vercel.app

• 2022

JoyFoodly

www.joyfoodly.com

2021 – present

web work portfolio

www.stephendewyerwebwork.com

2013 – 2017

∞ mile (Infinite Mile)

www.infinitemiledetroit.com

• 2008 – present

artist website

www.stephengdewyer.info

July 2013 - January 2017, Detroit, Michigan

- Designed, developed, deployed and maintained website featuring an online store for print anthologies and merchandise, generating thousands of dollars in revenue
- Directed three editing staff and 78 contributors to publish 94 essays and interviews, 51 artist projects, 26 reviews and 27 works of fiction or poetry
- Wrote successful grant applications
- Partnered with the University of Michigan Stamps School of Art & Design to produce two serial publications and conferences

technical training

Certificates in Software Development, Machine Learning, UX Design and Web Accessibility

Udemy 2021 – 2024

- Beginning C++ Programming From Beginner to Beyond
- Understanding TypeScript
- Machine Learning A-Z™: Al, Python & R + ChatGPT Bonus [2023]
- GraphQL by Example
- Svelte.js The Complete Guide (incl. Sapper.js)
- NodeJS The Complete Guide (MVC, REST APIs, GraphQL, Deno)
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux)
- Web Accessibility Training Course WCAG 2.1 Compliance
- The User Researcher's guide to UX discoveries

Certificates in Software Development and Leadership University of Michigan – Coursera

2020 - 2021

- JavaScript, jQuery, and JSON
- Interactivity with JavaScript
- Building Database Applications in PHP
- Introduction to Structured Query Language (SQL)
- Building Web Applications in PHP
- Intermediate PostgreSQL
- Database Design and Basic SQL in PostgreSQL
- Python Data Structures
- Python for Everybody
- Inspiring and Motivating Individuals

Certificates in UX Design

Interaction Design Foundation 2020

- UI Design Patterns for Successful Software
- Mobile User Experience (UX) Design
- Become a UX Designer from Scratch